[snorts]
For over eight years, I've been
publishing videos on this YouTube
channel. [music] In that time, I've also
come out with several books and audio
books. I've done all of this without
having ever shared anything about me
other than my name until now.
There are many reasons for why I've
never shown my face or shared anything
explicit about who I am or who's behind
the channel and books. One is simply
privacy. Another is maintaining a sense
of divide between my work, online life,
and personal life. Another, and perhaps
one of the biggest reasons, [music] is
that I never wanted me as an individual
to be the headline or focus of my work.
I didn't want a face or personality
explicitly entering and skewing the
frame. I think there's something
powerful about experiencing someone's
work in a relative vacuum of context. Of
course, no one ever fully escapes the
frame of their work. My voice is always
still there, both in a literal and
literary sense. [music] My choice of
topics, ideas, words, visuals, pacing,
and music that's always there and an
expression of me. Another reason is also
just fear. The fear of being perceived,
evaluated, reduced. Being perceived can
be unsettling on any level. Add the
reflection of hundreds of thousands, if
not millions of eyeballs, and it feels
like it's enough to burn a hole right
through your brain. I've also recently
been preparing to come out with a new
book, The Terrible Paradox of
Self-awareness. I'll talk more about it
in a moment, but if you're interested,
it comes out March 10th, and you can
pre-order it now through the link in the
description.
One thing that's become increasingly
clear to me recently, is that in a world
where more and more people don't really
make the stuff they make, at least not
in the way we've come to expect, for
better or for worse, hiding behind
ration for anonymity doesn't feel as
viable or meaningful anymore. People are
increasingly unsure of what's real and
how things are made, and for good
reasons. But seeing comments on work
where countless hours were dedicated to
every detail of every stage, suggesting
something's AI generated is a strange
and upsetting part of the technological
shift we're currently living through.
My main interest has been and remains
writing. Writing has brought me
everywhere figuratively [music]
into history, across the world, into my
conscious and subconscious mind, into
the perspectives of others. It has taken
me apart almost as many times [music] as
it has put me back together. I intend to
continue writing for as long as I can
see into the future. But with the future
that seems a bit blurry, anywhere I can
add clarity of authorship, of humanity,
of effort, and intention, I think it's
worth it. So, with that being said, here
I am. My name is Robert Pantano, and I'm
the writer and creator behind Pursuit of
Wonder, as well as books like The Art of
Living a Meaningless Existence and Notes
from the End of Everything, as well as
my upcoming book, The Terrible Paradox
of Self-awareness. [music]
Pursuit of Wonder actually began as a
book, a book about the wonders and
horrors of being alive. [music] It was
rejected by every publisher and agent
that I sent it to. At the time, a decade
or so ago, I was completely unknown, had
no audience and no platform, so this was
understandable. But instead of
abandoning the project, I took the
chapters I had written for the
manuscript, adapted them into videos for
YouTube, and posted them on this
channel. After pretty quickly running
out of initial material, I continue to
research, write, produce, and post more
videos. Since then, things have grown
beyond even my naivest expectations.
On the channel itself, it's been a
one-man operation since the beginning.
No team, no company, no backing. I do
all the writing, the editing, the
proofing, the animating, the voice over,
the audio mixing, the funding, and
logistics. [music] Of course, I've had
help along the way, especially outside
the channel, conversations, shared
thoughts, and help with things like
graphic design, and I'm grateful for all
of it. The timing of this moment is
pretty symbolic for me. My new upcoming
book will be the first one that's
traditionally published. All my other
books were self-published. I did
everything with limited resources and
reach. This new book, however, will be
available essentially everywhere books
are sold. In a way, this moment feels
like the final line segment, [music] the
connection point that closes that circle
I had started before Pursuit of Wonder
existed. That first early manuscript
never became a book, but it led to
Pursuit of Wonder, which eventually led
to the books I self-published, which
then led to this right now, to this book
and this moment.
The terrible paradox of self-awareness
explores many of these topics of
selfhood, of letting go, of embracing
uncertainty and expressing and becoming
oneself without restraint. It's about
what it means to be something in the
world that somehow knows it's something.
Something that doesn't quite understand
how or what that something is. It's for
those of us who seek to live well within
this absurd condition. to embrace the
uncertainty, to let go more, to care
less about what doesn't matter, and to
see the pains and struggles of human
existence and know that it's somehow all
worth it. On that note, if you've ever
found meaning in my work or it's
resonated with you in some way, I hope
you'll consider giving my new book a
read. It's an entirely new non-fiction
work of mine written from the ground up.
You can pre-order it now using the link
in the description. It comes out March
10th, and pre-orders genuinely make a
huge difference for the long-term
success of the book because it shows the
publisher and bookstores that it's worth
stocking more. If you do choose to
pre-order a copy, thank you so much in
advance. [music] It truly means a lot.
Moving forward, I plan to show up a bit
more in certain videos and perhaps a bit
more outside the channel. No big
changes, just occasionally showing up
peripherally. I also want to take this
opportunity to thank you directly.
Regardless of whether you order my
books, regardless of whether you've done
anything other than watch a single video
or read a single page, I sincerely
appreciate you. Even a few seconds of
your attention is something I don't take
for granted. I couldn't be any more
fortunate to be able to engage in and
write about what I do. And it has been a
privilege and honor to have been able to
do so for so long for so many people and
in a way that seems to resonate. And so
as always, thank you so much for
watching in general and see you next
video.